Arihant Jain

Computer Science | Expected: May 2022 | US Citizen | Portfolio: https://tinyurl.com/portfoliothearijain

Email: thearijain@gatech.edu | Cell: 678-294-7645 | http://www.github.com/thearijain | https://tinyurl.com/linkedin-thearijain

Professional Summary:

As a 3rd year computer science major at Georgia Tech with the knowledge of multiple software languages and real-life experience in technical areas, my course work, personal projects, and prior internships have prepared me for any challenges that may be presented to me at your organization. I highly suggest you check out the ReadMe files on my Github!

Extracurriculars:

TA | Teaching Assistant - Math 1554

- Attend three linear algebra lectures weekly in order to stay up to date on the course's content and material
- Prepare for and administer semi-weekly recitations complete with worksheets and group activities to aid students succeed in one of Tech's most challenging math classes

Skills

- Full Stack
- UI/UX
- .NET Development
- Github and Zenhub
- Database design/management
- Adobe Suite
- Microsoft Entity Framework
- Xcode/ Objective-C/ Swift/ Swift UI
- API development

Relevant Coursework:

Data Structures and Algorithms, Advanced Algorithms, Intro to A.I., Object-Oriented Programming, User Interface Design, Application Development,

Languages:

Java, Swift, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, C, Objective-C, Swift UI, C#

Profession | DJ 2014 - Current

- Have DJ'd for hundreds of clients and work for 3 different companies
- DJ events and venues such as weddings, sweet-sixteens, engagement parties, bars, lounges

EDUCATION:

Georgia Institute of Technology - Computer Science

GPA: 3.70

Concentrations: Artificial Intelligence & Computing and People

EXPERIENCE:

VMware | .NET Development Intern on iOS AirWatch Team

May 2020 - August 2020

- Utilized Entity Framework and .NET Core to create multiple internal APIs within cloud based microservices that are used across thousands of database tables and multiple cloud services within VMware
- Implemented factory design pattern and dependency injection in order to modularize my code as well as prepare it for unit testing
- Wrote overarching unit tests using mocking frameworks in order to ensure my code was ready for production

Tours Limited | Product Development Intern

May 2019 - August 2019

- Automated the company's weekly code base merging process across different environments through Powershell scripts
- Increased client-side website performance and reduced company codebase by writing and replacing one-instance functions with global functions in C#
- Increased employee efficiency by 90% by creating a function on the company webpage that allowed employee data inputs to be passed directly to the Visual Studio IDE; accomplished through Windows Native Messaging and Powershell scripts
- Assisted company in the process of moving their data to AWS servers

Tours Limited | Web Development Intern

February 2018 - May 2018

- Worked on building and designing webpages
- Company database management through SQL

PERSONAL PROJECTS:

(http://www.github.com/thearijain)

Barhop (Startup)

- A startup project that hopes to change the nightlife experience forever
- Currently formulating timelines, business plans, and intensely focusing on the development process of the application the startup life is very hard!

Vista Value (iOS)

- Expense tracking app created in hopes to alleviate the stress that comes with tracking your expenses

- Updates with live user data and has an amazing user experience, with over 50 categories of expenses to choose from and multiple ways to track your spending this app parallels some of the most advanced expense tracking platforms on the market Connect-4 (iOS)
- Created a game of Connect4 on iOS that allows users to play against a computer
- Working towards implementing Apple's Gameplay Kit to have an Al backend opponent
- Consists of a very efficient win-checking algorithm explained on my Github $\underline{\textit{Mix-IT}}$ (iOS)

2019

2020

2020

2019-2022

- Developed an application that allows users to DJ (mix music) through their fingertips.
- Front-end was designed through AdobeXD, back-end created through xCode and Swift